THE JUDGE RETURNS
판사가 돌아오다
What?
무엇?
Why is it empty?
왜 비어 있나요?
Those damn bastards!
이 빌어먹을 놈들아!
How did they hide so fast?
그들은 어떻게 그렇게 빨리 숨었나요?
Hey, calm down.
이봐, 진정해.
Why are we searching here? They cleared out a long time ago!
우리는 왜 여기서 찾고 있는 걸까요? 그들은 오래 전에 정리되었습니다!
The investment scammers
투자 사기꾼들
only rent this space
이 공간만 빌려주세요
for investment seminars and events.
투자 세미나 및 행사를 위한 행사입니다.
What?
무엇?
Hey, Seong-dae invested 2.9 billion won.
야, 성대씨가 29억원을 투자했다.
It's three billion in total.
총 30억입니다.
He'll catch on soon enough. Better wrap it up.
그는 곧 따라잡을 것이다. 마무리하는 것이 좋습니다.
I'm already on it.
나는 이미 그 일을 하고 있다.
I'm Seok Jeong-ho, alright?
저는 석정호예요, 그렇죠?
You're kidding me.
농담하는 거군요.
I put so much effort into this case!
나는 이 사건에 많은 노력을 기울였습니다!
Why would you ruin it like this?
왜 이렇게 망칠까요?
Can't believe you raided this office without a clue!
당신이 이 사무실을 습격했다니 믿을 수 없군요 아무 생각 없이!
Damn it.
젠장.
I was tipped off, okay?
나한테 정보를 받았어, 알았지?
What a joke.
정말 농담이에요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
There are cryptocurrency scammers in Gangnam.
암호화폐 사기꾼이 있다 강남에서.
- What? - Check the files I sent you
- 무엇? - 내가 보낸 파일을 확인해보세요
for further details.
자세한 내용은
CRIME CASE REPORT FOR MIRACLE ASIA'S INVESTMENT SCAM
범죄 사건 보고서 MIRACLE ASIA의 투자 사기에 대해
ALLEGED CRIMES COMMITTED PAST CHARGES
혐의가 있는 범죄 과거 청구 금액
THE MANAGEMENT DISAPPEARED IN 2020, WITH 500 MILLION DOLLARS OF DAMAGE
2020년에 경영진이 사라졌고, 5억 달러의 피해
Why did you raid this office?
왜 이 사무실을 급습했나요?
They're too smart. They must've caught on...
그들은 너무 똑똑해요. 그 사람들이 따라잡았나 봐요...
Hold on.
잠깐만요.
Yes, Mr. Lee.
네, 이씨.
Did you invest in Miracle Asia?
미라클아시아에 투자하셨나요?
No!
아니요!
What?
무엇?
This can't be right.
이것은 옳을 수 없습니다.
Where did they all go?
그 사람들은 다 어디로 갔나요?
Oh, no.
안 돼.
CEO'S OFFICE
CEO 사무실
These frauds!
이 사기꾼들아!
My money!
내 돈!
Mr. Lee
이씨
are you alright?
괜찮아?
It wasn't much money, right?
돈은 별로 안 들었죠?
How much did you invest?
얼마나 투자하셨나요?
You said you'd tell me!
나한테 말하겠다고 했잖아!
And that you'd wait two months!
그리고 당신은 두 달을 기다릴 것입니다!
When did I say that?
내가 언제 그런 말을 했나요?
And I wasn't behind the raid.
그리고 나는 그 습격의 배후에 있지 않았습니다.
Yes, Mr. Kang.
네, 강 선생님.
I got a call from the Future Talents Foundation.
로부터 전화를 받았습니다 미래인재재단입니다.
Oh, yes.
아, 그렇죠.
Five years of making donations sounds pretty good.
5년간의 기부 소리 꽤 좋아.
Send them 300 million won.
3억원을 보내주세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
- The street angel? - Yes, the angel.
- 거리의 천사요? - 응, 천사야.
- I'm Park Cheol-woo. - I'm Seok Jeong-ho.
- 박철우입니다. - 석정호입니다.
Nice to meet you. I'm Seok Jeong-ho.
만나서 반가워요. 저는 석정호입니다.
I'll bring you the best food to go with those drinks.
최고의 음식을 가져다줄게요 그 음료수와 함께 가자.
Han-young!
한영!
Three billion won!
30억 원!
Three billion...
30억...
You're paying me for the stage set and my acting, right?
당신은 나에게 무대 세트 비용을 지불하고 있어요 그리고 내 연기 맞지?
- Of course. - Really?
- 물론. - 정말?
You can't lie. You're a judge.
당신은 거짓말을 할 수 없습니다. 당신은 판사입니다.
I wouldn't do that.
나는 그렇게하지 않을 것입니다.
I'll give you all three billion won
30억 원 다 줄게
for setting the stage and for your acting.
무대를 준비하고 연기를 위해.
And when the time is right
그리고 때가 되면
donate it with a happy heart.
기쁜 마음으로 기부해 보세요.
Hey!
여기요!
Nothing's meaner than taking back a present.
더 심술궂은 건 없어 선물을 돌려받는 것보다
And nothing is better than sharing.
그리고 공유하는 것보다 더 좋은 것은 없습니다.
No!
아니요!
You're the best.
당신은 최고입니다.
No, I'm the worst!
아니, 내가 최악이야!
You always let Na-yeong win, but never me.
당신은 항상 나영이가 이기도록 놔두었지만 나는 그렇지 않았습니다.
You can stop now. I get it. You two are best friends.
이제 그만해도 됩니다. 알겠습니다. 너희 둘은 가장 친한 친구야.
Won't Sin-jin pass out in stress
신진이 스트레스 받으면 기절하지 않을까?
after realizing he's lost three billion?
그가 30억 달러를 잃었다는 걸 깨닫고 나서?
It'll be over before we even break his neck.
끝날 거야 그 사람 목이 부러지기 전에요.
No, I doubt that he'll be all that affected.
아니, 의심스럽다 그 사람이 그만큼 영향을 받을 거라고요.
He knows he can easily earn it back through blackmail or bribes.
그는 쉽게 돈을 돌려받을 수 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다 협박이나 뇌물을 통해.
What?
무엇?
So, all that work was meaningless?
그렇다면 그 일은 모두 의미가 없었다는 건가요?
Why meaningless?
왜 무의미합니까?
It united us as a team.
그것은 우리를 팀으로 하나로 묶었습니다.
- One team! - We now know our common enemies
- 한 팀! - 이제 우리는 공통의 적을 알게 되었습니다.
and how excellent we are at acting and thinking on our feet.
그리고 우리가 얼마나 뛰어난지 우리 발로 행동하고 생각하는 것.
Everyone will be so shocked to hear that the former President is
다들 들으면 너무 놀라실 거에요 전직 대통령이라고.
on Sin-jin's side.
신진 편에서.
- Alright, take your glasses. - Thanks.
- 알았어, 안경 가져가. - 감사해요.
- What was that? One team? - Yeah.
- 그게 뭐였죠? 한 팀? - 응.
Alright, Jin-a.
알았어, 진아.
For one team!
한 팀을 위해!
- Cheers!
- 건배!
One team!
한 팀!
We're one! Yes!
우리는 하나입니다! 예!
Try this. It's a delicacy.
이것을 시도해 보세요. 진미입니다.
Hey, imagine what would've happened had we not moved offices.
이봐, 무슨 일이 일어났을지 상상해봐 사무실을 옮기지 않았다면.
It was impossible to get Seong-dae to leave.
불가능했어요 성대를 떠나게 하려고.
Gosh, we were so close.
맙소사, 우리는 너무 가까웠어요.
Hearing about that office pisses me off.
그 사무실에 대한 이야기를 들으니 화가 난다.
How could you all keep it a secret?
어떻게 다들 비밀로 할 수 있었나요?
Well, I went over to help.
글쎄요, 제가 도와드리러 갔어요.
What if I didn't recognize you?
내가 당신을 알아보지 못하면 어떻게 되나요?
You recognized me right away.
당신은 나를 바로 알아보았습니다.
All those mean words
그 모든 나쁜 말들
about my driving and life!
내 운전과 생활에 대해!
Those words really came from your heart.
그 말은 정말로 당신의 마음에서 나온 것입니다.
Let's just say I was creative on the spot. It was all acting.
내가 그 자리에서 창의적이었다고 가정해보자. 다 연기였어요.
Ha, I doubt it.
하, 의심스럽습니다.
Come on, stop picking on me.
어서, 나 좀 그만 괴롭히세요.
So, what actually happened?
그렇다면 실제로 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
I tipped the prosecution about Miracle Asia.
검찰에 제보했어요 미라클 아시아에 대해서.
What? The prosecution?
무엇? 검찰?
We need the prosecution to raid the office
검찰이 사무실을 압수수색해야 한다
for the case to be dismissed without Seong-dae realizing who got him.
사건이 기각되려면 성대는 누가 그를 잡았는지 깨닫지 못한 채.
Hey
안녕
how am I supposed to know the prosecution is coming?
내가 어떻게 알겠어요? 검찰이 오나요?
On that note
그 메모에
let's set up another office.
사무실을 하나 더 차립시다.
Man, I knew you were smart!
야, 난 네가 똑똑한 줄 알았어!
MIRACLE ASIA HEADQUARTERS ADDRESS
MIRACLE ASIA 본사 주소
They moved offices already?
벌써 사무실을 옮겼나요?
Classic scammer move.
전형적인 사기꾼의 움직임.
Sure.
확신하는.
Headquarters or not
본사인지 아닌지
as long as they make my money grow.
그들이 내 돈을 늘려주는 한.
You knew it, didn't you?
당신은 그것을 알고 있었죠?
No!
아니요!
It's my first time hearing about it.
그것에 대해 듣는 것은 처음입니다.
Wow, your acting is on point!
와, 연기력이 딱이네요!
What is this? It's not a restaurant nor a food stand.
이게 뭔가요? 식당도 아니고 음식 파는 곳도 아닙니다.
Hello!
안녕하세요!
- Hello! - Hey.
- 안녕하세요! - 여기요.
- Here. - Hello.
- 여기. - 안녕하세요.
- Thank you. - Sit here.
- 감사합니다. - 여기 앉으세요.
- She's...
- 그녀는...
How are you?
잘 지내세요?
Hello, I'm Song Na-yeon.
안녕하세요 송나연 입니다.
Hello, I'm Seok Jeong-ho.
안녕하세요 석정호 입니다.
What's with that voice?
그 목소리는 뭐죠?
Have a seat.
앉으세요.
Here.
여기.
I cooked this squid stir-fry.
저는 이 오징어볶음을 요리했어요.
- Wow! - Have a glass.
- 우와! - 한잔 드세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You can beg me all you want
나한테 원하는 대로 빌어도 돼
and I'd still never eat there.
그리고 나는 아직도 거기에서 식사를 하지 않을 것입니다.
But why do I want to cry?
그런데 왜 울고 싶은 걸까요?
This is so annoying!
이건 정말 짜증나는 일이에요!
SEOUL CENTRAL DISTRICT COURT
서울중앙지방법원
SENIOR PRESIDING JUDGE KANG SIN-JIN
재판장 강신진
What the hell is this?
이게 대체 뭐야?
You said you'd sort it out. You told me to trust you!
정리하겠다고 하셨습니다. 당신을 믿으라고 했잖아요!
Did I ever say I couldn't sort it out?
내가 정리할 수 없다고 말한 적이 있었나요?
So, what's your plan now?
그럼 이제 당신의 계획은 무엇입니까?
Forget becoming the Chief Justice.
대법원장이 되는 것을 잊어라.
My son is about to make me lose my Justice title!
내 아들이 나를 잃게 만들려고 해요 내 정의 타이틀!
Your son's trial will be over soon
당신 아들의 재판은 곧 끝날 거예요
and you'll become the Chief Justice.
그리고 당신은 대법원장이 될 것입니다.
Are you
당신은
really sure about this?
정말 확실해요?
The trial was unexpected
재판은 예상치 못한 일이었다
but that won't change anything.
하지만 그것은 아무것도 바꾸지 않을 것입니다.
You're sure about this?
확실해요?
But
하지만
now that it'll take more effort
이제 더 많은 노력이 필요할 테니
with your son's unexpected case
아들의 예상치 못한 사건으로
you'll need to give me what I want.
당신은 내가 원하는 것을 나에게 주어야합니다.
Justice Hwang's son's life is
황 판사 아들의 삶은
right in your hands.
바로 당신의 손에 있습니다.
It's like you won the lottery.
복권에 당첨된 것과 같습니다.
Justice Hwang's son's life is in my hands
황 판사 아들의 생명은 내 손에 달렸다
but nobody's approached me yet.
하지만 아직 아무도 나에게 접근하지 않았습니다.
As if
마치
someone is stopping them.
누군가가 그들을 막고 있습니다.
You cast the bait yourself
스스로 미끼를 던지는군요
so hunt him yourself, too.
그러니 직접 사냥해 보세요.
Tae-seong isn't a bait. He's being held hostage.
태성은 미끼가 아니다. 그는 인질로 잡혀있습니다.
I'm not conducting a trial.
나는 재판을 진행하지 않습니다.
It's a hostage situation.
인질이 된 상황입니다.
The record of your illegal funds
불법 자금 기록
when you worked for the National Election Commission.
당신이 일했을 때 중앙선거관리위원회를 위해.
Bring that to me.
그걸 나에게 가져오세요.
I don't know what you're talking about.
무슨 말을 하는지 모르겠어요.
Do you really not know?
정말 모르시나요?
No, I don't.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
So, you're choosing to be a heartless father.
그래서 당신은 다음을 선택하고 있습니다. 마음이 없는 아버지.
By the way
그런데
your son will receive the maximum sentence possible.
네 아들이 받을 것이다 가능한 최대 형량.
You don't think I can stop a junior judge with a single call
내가 하급 판사를 막을 수 없을 거라고 생각하시죠? 전화 한 번으로
with my huge networks?
내 거대한 네트워크에?
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
That newbie judge only listens to me.
그 초보 판사는 내 말만 듣는다.
Haven't you made enough calls already?
이미 전화를 충분히 하지 않았나요?
You must know
당신은 알아야합니다
you have zero power over your son's trial
당신은 당신 아들의 재판에 대해 아무런 권한이 없습니다
pretty well by now.
지금쯤이면 꽤 괜찮아요.
Anyway, I got your message.
어쨌든, 당신의 메시지를 받았습니다.
Regardless of the trial
재판과 상관없이
I'll make you the Chief Justice.
당신을 대법원장으로 만들어 드리겠습니다.
The file exposes
파일이 노출됩니다.
not only multiple assemblymen
다수의 국회의원뿐만 아니라
but also the illegal funds for the former and current Presidents.
불법자금도 마찬가지 역대 대통령과 현직 대통령을 위해.
You sure you can handle that?
당신이 그걸 감당할 수 있다고 확신해요?
I wouldn't have bitten off
물지도 않았을 텐데
what I couldn't chew.
내가 씹지 못했던 것.
Justice Hwang.
황 판사님.
The court hereby orders
법원은 이에 명령한다.
Defendant Lee Bong-seok
피고인 이봉석
to one year and six months of imprisonment.
1년 6개월까지 투옥의.
Hwang Nam-yong.
황남용.
I don't care what you give Sin-jin.
나는 당신이 신진에게 무엇을 주든 상관하지 않습니다.
You'll never become the Chief Justice.
당신은 결코 대법원장이 될 수 없습니다.
I'll do everything it takes to stop you
나는 당신을 막기 위해 필요한 모든 것을 할 것입니다
even if you were to sell your soul.
영혼을 팔아도 마찬가지다.
Why haven't you sent the money
왜 돈을 보내지 않았나요?
to the Future Talents Foundation?
미래인재재단에?
I think we should re-negotiate on the donation period.
내 생각엔 우리가 다시 협상해야 할 것 같아 기부 기간에.
No, a five-year donation period isn't a bad deal.
아니 기부기간 5년 나쁜 거래는 아닙니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Is something wrong?
뭔가 문제가 있나요?
- Mr. Kang. - Tell me.
- 강 선생님. - 말해 주세요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I've been scammed.
저는 사기를 당했습니다.
What?
무엇?
I invested some money into an Asian cryptocurrency scam
돈을 좀 투자했어요 아시아 암호화폐 사기에 연루되다
and the prosecution ruined my plan by suddenly raiding them.
검찰이 내 계획을 망쳤어 갑자기 그들을 습격해서.
I had no idea.
나는 전혀 몰랐다.
You invested your money, knowing it was a scam?
돈을 투자하셨고, 사기인 줄 알았어?
Yes. But...
예. 하지만...
Prosecutor Park promised a heads-up
박 검사는 사전 경고를 약속했다.
before raiding them
그들을 습격하기 전에
so I thought it'd be safe.
그래서 안전할 거라고 생각했어요.
But someone unexpected came along...
그런데 뜻밖의 누군가가 나타났는데...
That's enough.
그것으로 충분합니다.
How much did you lose?
얼마나 잃었나요?
All three billion won.
모두 30억 원.
You've really lost your mind.
당신은 정말로 정신을 잃었습니다.
I can find them.
나는 그들을 찾을 수 있습니다.
Prosecutor Park has been investigating
박 검사가 수사 중이다.
so I know he'll find them.
그래서 나는 그가 그것을 찾을 것이라는 것을 압니다.
So?
그래서?
What if they do get arrested?
그들이 체포되면 어떻게 되나요?
What will you tell the prosecution?
검찰에 뭐라고 말할 겁니까?
How will you explain where you got the three billion won?
어떻게 설명할 것인가? 그 30억 원은 어디서 났어?
That I gave it to you?
내가 당신에게 준 거라고요?
I'll do everything to get the money back.
돈을 돌려받을 수 있도록 최선을 다하겠습니다.
No!
아니요!
Don't bother doing anything.
아무것도 하지 마세요.
Stay low and invisible
몸을 낮추고 눈에 띄지 않게 유지하세요
until I call you.
내가 전화할 때까지.
Just stay alive.
그냥 살아있어.
I'm ready.
난 준비됐어.
HWANG NAM-YONG
황남용
I'll send the judge on your son's case tomorrow.
판사를 보내겠다 내일 당신 아들 사건에 대해요.
SENIOR PRESIDING JUDGE KANG SIN-JIN
재판장 강신진
You called me?
나한테 전화했어?
Meet up with Nam-yong.
남용을 만나보세요.
He has something for you.
그는 당신을 위해 뭔가를 가지고 있습니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
And here.
그리고 여기.
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
So, you're the judge on the case.
그럼 당신이 이 사건의 판사이군요.
I've seen you at the Central Court.
중앙법원에서 봤어요.
Yes, I've only briefly introduced myself.
네, 간단하게 제 소개만 했습니다.
Is that right?
그렇죠?
I'm sure you know Tae-seong is my son.
태성이 내 아들인 건 너도 알겠지.
How do you plan on closing the case?
사건을 어떻게 종결할 계획인가요?
What do you mean, sir?
무슨 뜻인가요?
I guess you haven't heard yet.
아직 들어보시지 못한 것 같아요.
I'll tell you now, then.
그럼 지금부터 말씀드리겠습니다.
Announce Tae-seong as not guilty.
태성을 무죄로 선언한다.
Let's say he was misled
그 사람이 속았다고 해보자.
to think his teaching assistantship and internship
그의 조교직을 생각하다 그리고 인턴쉽
counted as work experience.
근무 경력으로 간주됩니다.
I'll be forever grateful once you close the case well.
영원히 감사할 거예요 일단 케이스를 잘 닫으세요.
And
그리고
make sure to pass this on to Sin-jin.
신진이한테 꼭 전해줘.
If it's about the final verdict, I've already heard about your history.
최종 판결에 관한 것이라면, 나는 이미 당신의 역사에 대해 들었습니다.
I hear you wrote the verdict yourself last time.
당신이 직접 평결을 썼다고 들었습니다. 지난번에.
If that's what you want
그게 당신이 원하는 거라면
I'll happily go to that length for you.
나는 당신을 위해 기꺼이 그 길이까지 갈 것입니다.
Could you please write one this time, too?
이번에도 하나 써주시겠어요?
Sure.
확신하는.
I just need a few days to write it.
그냥 쓰는데 며칠 걸리네요.
A person who injures the credit of another by circulating false facts
타인의 신용을 훼손한 자 허위 사실을 유포하여
or through fraudulent means
아니면 부정한 방법으로
shall be punished by imprisonment with labor for less than five years
징역형에 처해진다. 5년 미만의 노동
or by a fine not exceeding 15 million won.
또는 1,500만원 이하의 벌금에 처해집니다.
What do you think you're doing?
지금 뭐하고 있는 것 같나요?
Just wanted to help you write the verdict.
단지 당신이 평결을 작성하는 데 도움을 주고 싶었을 뿐입니다.
Tae-seong lied about his work experience to apply for the job at JB
태성이 직장 경력을 거짓말했다 JB에 지원하기 위해
which is fraudulent
사기적인 것
and an obstruction of business
그리고 업무방해
for disrupting JB's hiring process.
JB의 채용 과정을 방해한 혐의로요.
A son of a Justice should be an inspiring example to society, not this.
정의의 아들은 이렇게 되어야 한다 사회에 고무적인 예가 아니라 이것이 아닙니다.
I'd say a year and a half in prison sounds about right.
1년 반 동안 감옥에 갇힌 것 같아요 맞는 것 같네요.
What the hell are you going on about?
도대체 무슨 일을 하는 겁니까?
You even used your authority
넌 권한까지 행사했지
to make JB forge Tae-seong's scores so he could be hired.
JB가 태성의 점수를 위조하게 만들기 위해 그래서 그는 고용될 수 있었습니다.
Since the public despises
대중이 멸시하니까
anyone using their powerful dads for their own success
강력한 아빠를 이용하는 사람은 누구나 자신의 성공을 위해
he'll have to serve
그 사람은 봉사해야 할 거야
a year and a half without exceptions.
예외 없이 1년 반.
You think you can continue being a judge after pulling this?
당신은 계속 판사를 할 수 있다고 생각하는가? 이거 뽑고 나면?
You're the one who should end your career in court.
끝내야 할 사람은 너야 법정에서의 경력.
What?
무엇?
How dare you blackmail a Justice?
감히 판사를 협박하는 겁니까?
How dare you?
어떻게 감히?
Tae-seong will serve
태성이 봉사할게
exactly a year and a half in jail.
정확히 1년 반 동안 감옥에 갇혔습니다.
What?
무엇?
HWANG NAM-YONG'S TRANSACTION RECORDS FOR ALL BRIBES RECEIVED
황남용의 거래기록 뇌물을 받은 경우
This was over a decade ago.
이것은 10여 년 전의 일이었습니다.
How do you have this?
이거 어떻게 갖고 있어요?
INVESTIGATION RECORD, CONFIDENTIAL TARGET: HWANG NAM-YONG
조사 기록, 기밀 대상 : 황남용
CONFIRMATION OF TRANSACTION
거래 확인
WITNESS: HAN TAE-HWA POSITION: SECRETARY AT S GROUP
증인: 한태화 직위: S그룹 비서
TESTIFYING IN THE INVESTIGATION ROOM, SEOUL CENTRAL DISTRICT PROSECUTORS' OFFICE
조사실에서 증언을 하는데, 서울중앙지방검찰청
HWANG NAM-YONG'S TRANSACTION RECORDS FOR ALL BRIBES RECEIVED
황남용의 거래기록 뇌물을 받은 경우
RECIPIENT: HWANG NAM-YONG
수신자: 황남용
TESTIMONY
증언
I WAS BORN ON OCTOBER 22, 1964, AND I WORK FOR S CONSTRUCTION
나는 1964년 10월 22일에 태어났습니다. 그리고 나는 S 건설에서 일해요
YOUR HONOR, I WAS HIT IN THE HEAD BY ONE OF THE PROTESTING RESIDENTS
판사님, 저는 머리를 맞았습니다 항의하는 주민 중 한 사람의 말
MY BOSS IS VERY STRONG. HE PROTECTED ME
내 상사는 매우 강하다. 그는 나를 보호했다
INVESTIGATION RECORD, CONFIDENTIAL
조사 기록, 기밀
You took bribes from Mr. Jang Tae-sik of S Construction
뇌물을 받았잖아 S건설 장태식 대표님
and ruled in favor of a con man who staged his injury.
그리고 사기꾼에게 유리한 판결을 내렸어요 부상을 입힌 사람.
What a verdict needs is justice and common sense.
판결에 필요한 것은 정의와 상식.
But you framed
하지만 당신은 액자에 넣었어요
Plaintiff Lee Bong-seok as the perpetrator
원고 이봉석이 가해자
and sentenced him to a year and a half in jail.
그리고 그에게 형을 선고했다 징역 1년 6개월.
Your verdict
귀하의 평결
robbed a family
가족을 털었다
of its father
그 아버지의
and husband.
그리고 남편.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Don't tell me...
말하지 마세요 ...
That's right.
맞습니다.
The son who had his father robbed for a year and a half
아버지의 물건을 빼앗은 아들 1년 반 동안
all because of you.
다 너 때문이야.
So...
그래서...
you want an apology from me now?
지금 나한테 사과받고 싶은 거야?
What's the point in getting an apology?
사과를 받아도 무슨 소용이 있나요?
When you won't even be sincere.
솔직하지도 않을 때.
That's right.
좋아요.
But you're the same.
하지만 당신도 똑같습니다.
All that talk about justice
정의에 대해 말하는 모든 것
yet what you want on my son's verdict is
하지만 당신이 내 아들의 판결에서 원하는 것은
revenge, not justice.
복수가 아니라 정의.
It doesn't matter if I get fired or my son ends up in jail.
해고당해도 상관없어 아니면 내 아들이 감옥에 갇히게 됩니다.
What difference does that make for you?
그것이 당신에게 어떤 변화를 가져오나요?
I don't know if you know it yet
아직 알고 계실지 모르겠지만
but I'm the next Chief Justice.
하지만 제가 차기 대법원장이에요.
So
그래서
let past stay in the past
과거를 과거에 머물게 하라
and move on to the future with me.
나와 함께 미래를 향해 나아가세요.
I'll compensate you for the past well enough.
지난 일은 보상해줄게 충분합니다.
I'm more curious about the present.
나는 현재가 더 궁금하다.
I'm not sure if what I want is revenge or justice.
잘 모르겠어요 내가 원하는 것이 복수인지 정의인지.
But in this moment
하지만 지금 이 순간
I just can't stand the fact
난 그 사실을 참을 수가 없어
that someone like you
너 같은 사람이
has power and authority in court.
법정에서 권력과 권위를 가지고 있습니다.
Think about how far I can get you
내가 당신을 얼마나 멀리까지 데려갈 수 있을지 생각해 보세요.
once I become the Chief Justice.
일단 내가 대법원장이 되면.
Seize the chance
기회를 잡아라
when you can.
당신이 할 수 있을 때.
I'm the one giving you a chance.
나는 당신에게 기회를 주는 사람입니다.
Start by retiring as a judge. It doesn't suit you.
판사직을 은퇴하는 것부터 시작하세요. 그것은 당신에게 적합하지 않습니다.
That's the only way your son will return home.
그게 유일한 방법이야 당신의 아들은 집으로 돌아올 것입니다.
You have no idea how badly I wanted to kill you.
당신은 전혀 모른다 내가 얼마나 당신을 죽이고 싶었는지.
A writer once asked himself
어느 작가가 스스로에게 물었다.
"Can the past help the present?"
"과거가 현재를 도울 수 있을까?"
And here's what I want to ask myself.
그리고 여기 제가 스스로에게 묻고 싶은 것이 있습니다.
Can myself from my past life
내 전생에서 나 자신이 될 수 있습니까?
help me in the present?
지금은 나 좀 도와줘?
Am I still making the right choices
나는 아직도 올바른 선택을 하고 있는가?
for the better future?
더 나은 미래를 위해?
COURT
법원
Did you assign Judge Lee
이 판사를 배정하셨나요?
for my son's case on purpose?
내 아들 사건을 일부러?
As unfortunate as it is for you
당신에게도 불행한 일이지만
I guess karma is a real thing.
카르마는 진짜인 것 같아요.
What about the documents?
서류는 어떻습니까?
Did you write them?
당신이 썼나요?
I was
나는
your assistant judge then.
그럼 당신의 부판사님.
You took bribes from defendants
당신은 피고인에게서 뇌물을 받았습니다.
and colluded with them all the time.
그리고 항상 그들과 공모했습니다.
So, you go behind my back like this?
그럼 이렇게 내 등뒤로 가?
There's not even anything in it for you.
당신을 위한 것은 아무것도 없습니다.
Because truth can also be powerful
진실도 강력할 수 있으니까요
though that's rarely the case.
하지만 그런 경우는 거의 없습니다.
You struck me for no reason.
당신은 이유 없이 나를 때렸습니다.
Do you realize what your little punch has caused?
당신은 알고 있습니까? 네 작은 펀치 때문에 무슨 일이 일어났지?
That rascal told me to end my career!
그 악당이 나한테 내 경력을 끝내라고 했어!
Otherwise, he insisted
그렇지 않으면 그는 주장했다
he'd sentence my son to jail for a year and a half!
그 사람은 내 아들을 감옥에 보내려고 했어 1년 반 동안!
That's interesting.
흥미롭네요.
Regardless of what Judge Lee told you
이 판사가 당신에게 무슨 말을 했는지 상관없이
you'll become the Chief Justice.
당신은 대법원장이 될 것입니다.
And your son will also be home soon.
그리고 당신의 아들도 곧 집에 올 것입니다.
What?
무엇?
I'm not in the mood for jokes.
나는 농담할 기분이 아니다.
I'm not joking.
농담하는 게 아닙니다.
Think about all the wrongs you've done.
당신이 행한 모든 잘못에 대해 생각해보십시오.
This is just a small price to pay.
이것은 지불해야 할 작은 대가일 뿐입니다.
So
그래서
is this really the end of it?
정말 이게 끝인가요?
But Judge Lee is still the judge on the case.
하지만 이 판사는 여전히 판사다. 사건에.
Words have power.
말에는 힘이 있습니다.
Whose words do you think have more power
누구의 말이 더 힘이 있다고 생각하시나요?
Judge Lee's or mine?
이 판사의 것인가요, 아니면 내 것인가요?
You'd better own up
당신은 자신을 소유하는 것이 좋습니다
to what you just said.
방금 말한 것에 대해.
I apologize.
사과드립니다.
What? For what?
무엇? 무엇을 위해?
For Seong-dae.
성대를 위해서.
I knew he was into investing
나는 그가 투자에 관심이 있다는 것을 알았습니다.
but I had no idea he'd do something so ridiculous.
하지만 난 전혀 몰랐어 그 사람은 정말 말도 안 되는 짓을 할 거예요.
I should've watched him more closely.
나는 그를 좀 더 자세히 관찰했어야 했다.
How's that your fault?
그게 어떻게 네 잘못이야?
It's my fault for leaving money with such an idiot.
돈 놔둔 내 잘못이야 그런 바보와 함께.
No.
아니요.
I'll work even harder
더욱 열심히 하겠습니다
so you don't run into more problems.
그러면 더 이상 문제가 발생하지 않습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Let's just move on. Don't make it a bigger issue.
계속 진행합시다. 더 큰 문제로 만들지 마세요.
We're making the Chief Justice here.
우리는 여기서 대법원장을 만들고 있습니다.
Three billion won isn't worth jeopardizing that.
30억은 아깝다 그것을 위험에 빠뜨리는 것.
Cheers.
건배.
The only ones who knew Seong-dae had three billion won were
아는 사람만 알았지 성대에는 30억이 있었다.
you, me
너, 나
and Han-young.
그리고 한영.
Sorry? What do you mean?
죄송합니다? 무슨 뜻이에요?
We have to see
우리는 봐야 해
what Han-young is really like.
한영이 진짜 어떤 사람인지.
So, did you bring it?
그럼, 가져왔어?
Did you check the file?
파일을 확인하셨나요?
No, sir.
아니요, 선생님.
You must be dying to know what Nam-yong is handing over to me.
당신은 정말 알고 싶어 죽겠어요 남용이가 나에게 건네는 것.
I figured you'd tell me if it was something I needed to know.
나는 당신이 나에게 말할 줄 알았는데 그것이 내가 알아야 할 것이라면.
There are some impressive devices these days.
인상적인 장치가 있습니다 요즘.
If you accessed this file
이 파일에 접근했다면
I'll be able to see it.
나는 그것을 볼 수 있을 것이다.
ALLOW DEVICE TO CONNECT
장치 연결 허용
RECORD OF ILLEGAL FUNDS
불법 자금 기록
ILLEGAL FUNDS FOR FORMER PRESIDENTS
전직 대통령에 대한 불법자금
ILLEGAL FUNDS FOR FORMER PRESIDENT PARK GWANG-TO
불법자금 박광토 전 대통령을 위하여
VIEW RECORD OF DEVICE USE
장치 사용 기록 보기
FILES ACCESSED: 0 TIMES FILES COPIED: 0 TIMES
액세스된 파일: 0회 복사된 파일: 0회
You're awfully obedient for a young man.
당신은 청년치고는 정말 순종적이네요.
If I were you, I would've opened it out of curiosity.
내가 너라면, 호기심에 열어봤을 겁니다.
Let me pour you one.
하나 부어드릴게요.
Yes, Ms. Song.
네, 송 선생님.
I talked to an expert
전문가와 통화했어요
and you'll be really screwed if you open it.
그러면 너 진짜 망할 거야 열면.
It tracks all the times the files are accessed and copied.
그것은 항상 추적합니다 파일에 액세스하고 복사합니다.
You'd better not do anything with it.
그것에 대해 아무것도 하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
There's a first for everything.
모든 일에는 처음이 있습니다.
That's where your initial resolve lies.
그것이 바로 당신의 초기 결심이 있는 곳입니다.
Here.
여기.
I'm walking on thin ice
살얼음판 위를 걷고 있어요
to gain Sin-jin's trust.
신진의 신뢰를 얻기 위해.
One slip, and it's game over.
한 번 실수하면 게임이 끝납니다.
But so many forget about their first resolves.
하지만 너무 많은 사람들이 잊어버린다 그들의 첫 결심에 대해.
But that's
하지만 그건
none of my business.
내 일은 아니야.
You know why?
이유를 아시나요?
Because you have
왜냐하면 당신은
endless people wanting to be on your side.
당신 편이 되고 싶어하는 사람들은 끝없이 많습니다.
Exactly.
정확히.
So, don't forget yours.
그러므로 당신의 것을 잊지 마십시오.
Hey, welcome back.
안녕하세요, 돌아온 것을 환영합니다.
Thanks. Where's Mother?
감사해요. 어머니는 어디 계시나요?
She's asleep. She said she was tired.
그녀는 자고 있어요. 그녀는 피곤하다고 말했다.
- Father. - Yeah?
- 아버지. - 응?
Why don't I join you for a drink? It's been a while.
나도 같이 한잔하는 게 어때? 오랜만이에요.
Sure.
확신하는.
Oh, I was just going to have one glass.
아, 그냥 한 잔만 마시려고 했는데요.
Wow.
우와.
Here.
여기.
Father.
아버지.
Yeah?
응?
I was
나는
there.
거기.
I can't stop thinking about it.
나는 그것에 대해 생각하는 것을 멈출 수 없습니다.
When you were protesting
시위하던 시절
against the redevelopment.
재개발을 반대합니다.
Why are you still stuck on that?
왜 아직도 그것에 매달리고 있나요?
You should forget about it.
잊어 버려야합니다.
- When you passed out... - Forget about it all.
- 기절했을 때... - 다 잊어버려요.
Whatever it is, just forget about it.
그것이 무엇이든 간에, 그냥 잊어버리세요.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Don't come this way! Stop!
이쪽으로 오지 마세요! 멈추다!
Don't hurt us!
우리를 해치지 마세요!
Father?
아버지?
No!
아니요!
Father!
아버지!
Even the stones on the ground have their own stories.
땅바닥에 있는 돌에도 그들만의 이야기.
And even the newest newborns have
그리고 심지어 갓 태어난 신생아들도
as many stories as the days they've lived.
그들이 살아온 날만큼 많은 이야기.
So
그래서
in a world of endless stories intertwined with each other
끝없는 이야기가 얽혀있는 세계에서 서로
who doesn't feel wronged or blamed?
누가 잘못되거나 비난받지 않습니까?
If you stay stuck on feeling wronged
억울한 느낌에 계속 갇혀 있다면
how can your heart embrace
어떻게 네 마음이 포용할 수 있겠어?
the more important emotions that it should feel?
더 중요한 감정 그게 느껴져야 한다고?
People don't say they're fine
사람들은 괜찮다고 말하지 않지
because they're really fine.
정말 괜찮으니까요.
So
그래서
whatever is going on inside of you
네 안에서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있든
just keep telling yourself it's fine
그냥 계속 괜찮다고 스스로에게 말해줘
and it'll all be fine one day.
그리고 언젠가는 다 괜찮을 거예요.
I like my eggs
나는 내 계란을 좋아한다
sunny-side-up.
써니사이드업.
Don't break the yolk.
노른자를 깨지 마십시오.
Thanks.
감사해요.
It's fine.
괜찮습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
How much time do I have?
시간이 얼마나 있나요?
I just want to live like this
난 그냥 이렇게 살고 싶어
until the end.
끝까지.
Oh, gosh.
아, 이런.
Stop drinking before bed.
잠자리에 들기 전에 술을 마시지 마십시오.
You remember that girl?
그 여자 기억나?
The one we met shortly after I was released from jail.
우리가 만난 사람 감옥에서 풀려난 직후였습니다.
Of course.
물론.
How can I forget about her?
내가 어떻게 그녀를 잊을 수 있나요?
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Do you need help?
도움이 필요하신가요?
Did your mom tell you to come?
엄마가 오라고 했어?
Oh, I...
아, 난...
Well...
음...
Here you go.
여기요.
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
- Hey! - Miss!
- 여기요! - 놓치다!
Oh, well...
아, 글쎄...
My dad isn't a bad man.
우리 아빠는 나쁜 사람이 아니에요.
Please don't resent him so much.
그 사람을 너무 원망하지 마시기 바랍니다.
Hey...
안녕...
Hello
안녕하세요
my name is Kim Jin-a.
제 이름은 김진아예요.
I'm the daughter of Kim Seok-tae
저는 김석태 딸이에요
the man whom you supposedly beat up
당신이 때린 것으로 추정되는 그 남자
and sued you.
그리고 당신을 고소했어요.
I know you didn't do anything wrong.
나는 당신이 아무 잘못도 하지 않았다는 것을 압니다.
Of course, I also know
물론 나도 알아
you didn't hurt my dad.
당신은 우리 아버지를 해치지 않았습니다.
My dad isn't a bad man
우리 아빠는 나쁜 사람이 아니야
but he did something bad so he could raise me.
그런데 그 사람이 나쁜 짓을 했어 그래서 그 사람이 나를 키울 수 있었어.
I'd love to tell my dad
아빠한테 말하고 싶어
to stop working in such an evil job
그런 나쁜 일을 그만 두려고
but I've been pretending not to know about his job
하지만 난 그런 척을 했어 그 사람 직업에 대해 몰라서
because I don't want to break his heart.
그 사람의 마음을 아프게 하고 싶지 않기 때문이다.
My Jin-a.
나의 진아.
You're a real grown-up, like everyone else.
당신은 진짜 어른이군요. 다른 사람들처럼.
Of course.
물론.
I even work late nights
늦은 밤에도 일해요
and have staff dinners.
그리고 직원 저녁식사를 하세요.
You've never had those, have you?
당신은 그런 것을 먹어 본 적이 없군요, 그렇죠?
Are you asking if I'm jealous?
내가 질투하는지 묻는 거야?
Are you?
당신은?
Of course.
물론.
I'm so, so jealous.
정말 너무 질투나요.
Here.
여기.
Apparently, this brings you luck.
분명히 이것은 당신에게 행운을 가져다줍니다.
Broke people like us
우리처럼 망가진 사람들
have nothing but luck to count on.
믿을 수 있는 것은 행운밖에 없습니다.
So, every time I saw a four-leaf clover
그래서 네잎 클로버를 볼 때마다
I made sure to pluck it.
꼭 뽑아봤습니다.
But now that I see it
그런데 지금 보니
having you as my daughter was my biggest luck.
당신을 내 딸로 둔 것 내 가장 큰 행운.
You're my Ace of Clubs.
당신은 나의 클럽 에이스입니다.
The four-leaf clover in this letter is
이 편지에 있는 네잎 클로버는
what my dad and I love most.
아빠와 내가 가장 좋아하는 것.
Dad said we had to wish for luck
아빠는 우리가 행운을 빌어야 한다고 말했어
because we had nothing else to count on.
왜냐하면 우리가 더 이상 의지할 것이 없었기 때문입니다.
That's why he loves these clovers so much.
그래서 그는 이 클로버를 그토록 좋아합니다.
A four-leaf clover may be the only thing
네잎 클로버가 유일한 것일 수도 있습니다.
I can give you now
이제 줄 수 있어
but once I grow older
하지만 일단 나이가 들면
I'll compensate you for my dad's wrongdoing.
보상해드릴게요 아버지의 잘못 때문에.
I'm so sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Sincerely, Kim Seok-tae's daughter, Kim Jin-a.
진심으로 김석태 딸님, 김진아.
Her name was
그녀의 이름은
Jin-a, right? Kim Jin-a?
진아 맞죠? 김진아?
Yeah.
응.
She asked us to forgive her dad.
그녀는 우리에게 아버지를 용서해달라고 요청했습니다.
She wrote that he was doing bad things to raise her
그녀는 그가 나쁜 짓을 하고 있다고 썼다 그녀를 키우기 위해
but he wasn't a bad man.
하지만 그 사람은 나쁜 사람이 아니었어요.
How does that make any sense, though?
그런데 그게 무슨 의미가 있나요?
You know
알잖아
we should've at least fed her a meal before she left.
우리는 최소한 그녀에게 식사를 줬어야 했는데 그녀가 떠나기 전에.
I hope she's doing fine.
그녀가 잘 지내길 바랍니다.
I sure do, too.
나도 마찬가지야.
Are you Mr. Kim Seok-tae's guardian?
김석태 씨의 보호자이신가요?
I urgently called you earlier
아까 급하게 전화했는데
because he was having breathing issues
호흡 문제가 있었기 때문에
but I should've waited a bit first.
하지만 먼저 좀 기다렸어야 했는데.
Sorry for calling you so late.
너무 늦게 전화해서 미안해요.
Interesting.
흥미로운.
I swear I've seen him somewhere.
맹세코 그 사람을 어디선가 본 적이 있어요.
Call her right now.
지금 당장 전화하세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Ms. Kim.
김 씨.
Ms. Kim!
김 선생님!
You can't do this!
당신은 이것을 할 수 없습니다!
I won't say anything
난 아무 말도 하지 않을 거야
about you guys having moved him to a different room
너희들이 그를 옮겼다는 것에 대해서 다른 방으로
without my permission.
내 허락 없이.
- Sorry? - Tell me
- 죄송합니다? - 말해봐
how much the VIP suite costs.
VIP 스위트 비용은 얼마입니까?
Oh, sure.
아, 물론이죠.
Damn, that's fresh.
젠장, 신선하네요.
Why don't you move your dad
아빠를 옮기는 게 어때?
back to the VIP suite?
VIP 스위트룸으로 돌아가시겠어요?
I'll take care of your father's hospital bills
내가 돌볼게 네 아버지의 병원비
and all the money you need
그리고 당신이 필요한 모든 돈
to maintain your status.
상태를 유지하기 위해.
Are you using money to win love
사랑을 얻기 위해 돈을 사용하고 있습니까?
because the letter didn't work?
편지가 통하지 않아서?
What you're doing is
당신이 하고 있는 일은
disrespecting your father.
아버지를 무례하게 대하는 것.
Byeon, what did the doctor say?
변 씨, 의사가 뭐라고 했어요?
It's Chronic...
만성이야..
It's Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy.
만성 외상성 뇌병증입니다.
Yeah. What causes that?
응. 그 원인은 무엇입니까?
Repetitive concussion
반복적인 뇌진탕
and head injuries.
그리고 머리 부상.
I see.
알겠어요.
That's interesting for a man with a successful prosecutor daughter.
남자한테는 그게 흥미롭지 성공한 검사 딸과 함께.
What kind of a life did he possibly live that led up to that?
그 사람은 과연 어떤 삶을 살았을까? 그게 그렇게 됐어?
He might as well have joined a gang
그 사람은 갱단에 가입했을 수도 있어요
if he wanted to get his head smashed.
만약 그가 머리를 박살내고 싶었다면.
Maybe he was one of them, just at the very bottom?
어쩌면 그 사람도 그 중 하나였을지도 모르죠. 그냥 제일 밑에?
Watch it.
조심하세요.
Oh, sorry.
아, 미안해요.
PATIENT: KIM SEOK-TAE
환자: 김석태
Dad!
아빠!
My gosh.
맙소사.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Yeah, I'm fine.
응, 난 괜찮아.
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 합니까?
Oh, gosh.
아, 이런.
Good work.
잘했어요.
You know
알잖아
this is at least 100 times healthier
이것이 적어도 100배는 더 건강하다
than the raw liver last time.
지난번 생간보다
You become mine
너는 내 것이 된다
if you drink this, okay?
이거 마시면 응?
I'm just kidding.
농담이에요.
Drink it
마셔
and all of this is yours.
그리고 이 모든 것은 당신 것입니다.
You hold quite a grudge.
당신은 꽤 원한을 품고 있습니다.
Of course.
물론.
There's nothing I hate more than people who pretend to be chill.
내가 싫어하는 건 하나도 없어 차가운 척하는 사람보다.
So, what now?
이제 어떻게 되나요?
Are you trying to befriend me now?
지금 나랑 친해지려고 하는 거야?
Well
음
I'd love to have such a pretty prosecutor be my friend, of course.
이렇게 예쁜 검사가 있었으면 좋겠다 물론 내 친구가 되어줘.
You know, I love oysters
아시다시피 저는 굴을 좋아해요
but the ones from you are too fishy.
하지만 당신이 만든 것들은 너무 수상해요.
I appreciate you keeping me entertained
나를 즐겁게 해주셔서 감사합니다
but be a little patient. Stop pestering me.
하지만 조금 참으세요. 나를 괴롭히지 마세요.
I'll come soon enough.
곧 올게요.
Okay.
좋아요.
But don't take too long.
하지만 너무 오래 걸리지는 마세요.
I hate being bored
지루한 건 싫어
as much as you do.
당신이 하는 만큼.
CALL HISTORY
통화 기록
ASSEMBLYMAN KANG JEONG-TAE TAKES HIS OWN LIFE AT HIS OFFICE
강정태 의원 사무실에서 스스로 목숨을 끊다
INVESTIGATION ON CHU YONG-JIN TO BE INTERRUPTED
추용진에 대한 조사 중단될 예정
I've confirmed everything about Haenal
해날에 대한 모든 것을 확인했습니다
S Group's case, and the other case.
S그룹의 경우, 또 다른 경우.
My guess was right about them all.
내 추측은 그들 모두에게 맞았습니다.
But there's no conclusive evidence yet.
하지만 아직 결정적인 증거는 없습니다.
The same goes with this.
이것도 마찬가지다.
Sin-jin...
신진...
Why do you think
왜 그렇게 생각하는가?
Han-young left this with you?
한영이가 이걸 두고 갔다고?
We'll know once he tells us.
그가 우리에게 말하면 우리는 알게 될 것입니다.
Is all of this true?
이 모든 것이 사실입니까?
Yes, based on everything I know.
네, 제가 아는 모든 것을 바탕으로 말씀드리겠습니다.
I'm sure he's done more evil things that I don't know about.
분명 그 사람은 더 나쁜 짓을 했을 거야 내가 모르는 것.
Since when did you know about Sin-jin?
언제부터 신진에 대해 알고 있었나요?
When I found
내가 찾았을 때
the draft dodger list at my parents' junkyard.
드래프트 다저스 명단 부모님 폐차장에서요.
Once I realized
일단 깨달았다
Sin-jin was the one going after that list
그 목록을 노린 건 신진이였어
I kept digging into him.
나는 계속해서 그를 파헤쳤다.
I knew it when you busted that serial killer
나는 그것을 알고 있었다 당신이 그 연쇄 살인범을 체포했을 때
in Chungcheongnam-do.
충청남도에서.
Why are you acting like a prosecutor? You're a judge!
왜 검사 흉내를 내는 겁니까? 당신은 판사입니다!
And you should've come to me first when you got this.
그리고 당신이 나에게 먼저 왔어야 했어요 당신이 이것을 얻었을 때.
I needed to gain Sin-jin's trust first.
먼저 신진이의 신뢰를 얻어야 했다.
And get a new car from him?
그리고 그에게서 새 차를 사주나요?
I told you I paid for that with a 60-month installment plan!
내가 그 비용을 지불했다고 말했잖아 60개월 할부 플랜으로!
- But it was so sudden. - So?
- 그런데 너무 갑작스러웠어요. - 그래서?
Life happens, okay?
인생은 일어나는 일이죠, 그렇죠?
I'm already...
나는 이미...
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
In fact
실제로
we're also conducting an internal investigation on him.
우리도 지휘하고 있어 그에 대한 내부 조사.
- Sorry? - Sin-jin has a bad reputation.
- 죄송합니다? - 신진이는 평판이 좋지 않아요.
But nobody dares to check if the rumors are true.
하지만 누구도 감히 확인하지 못해요 소문이 사실이라면.
It's as if messing with Sin-jin is
신진이를 건드리는 건 마치
doing the unfathomable.
알 수 없는 일을 하고 있습니다.
Tell me
말해봐
the real reason I need to become the Chief Justice.
내가 되어야 할 진짜 이유 대법원장.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
It's you again?
또 당신이에요?
Is this about Sin-jin?
이게 신진 얘기야?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
I need the Chief Justice to have my back
내 뒤를 지켜줄 대법원장이 필요해
in order for me to take on Sin-jin.
내가 신진을 상대하기 위해서.
I see.
알겠어요.
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
- How dare you... - But
- 어떻게 감히... - 하지만
Sin-jin isn't the final boss here.
신진은 여기서 최종보스가 아니다.
We had an idea when we began the internal investigation.
우리에겐 아이디어가 있었어 우리가 내부 조사를 시작했을 때.
Do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
who has his back?
등이 누구야?
This looks like a bag full of money.
이것은 마치 돈이 가득 들어 있는 가방처럼 보입니다.
Do you know who runs Suojae?
수오재를 운영하는 사람이 누구인지 아시나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
Park Gwang-to, the former President.
박광토 전 대통령.
This is Baek Yi-seok.
백이석입니다.
Hello, Mr. Baek.
안녕하세요, 백 선생님.
Are you confident about nominating me
나를 추천할 자신이 있나요?
as the next Chief Justice?
차기 대법원장은?
Have you made up your mind?
마음을 정하셨나요?
Yes, please go ahead with it.
네, 계속 진행해주세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
I'll gladly watch this audacious rookie's back.
즐겁게 시청하겠습니다 이 대담한 신인이 돌아왔습니다.
Thank you, sir!
감사합니다!
PRESIDING JUDGE KIM JIN-HAN
재판장 김진한
CALL HISTORY
통화 기록
JUDGE LEE HAN-YOUNG
판사 이한영
Judge Lee...
이 판사...
And Prosecutor Park?
그리고 박검사?
Lee Han-young and Park Cheol-woo...
이한영과 박철우..
There's definitely something going on.
확실히 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 것 같아요.
MR.KANG: KILL HWANG TAE-SEONG AND STAGE IT AS A SUICIDE
강씨: 황태성을 죽여라 그리고 자살로 생각하세요
CALL HISTORY
통화 기록
This is Prosecutor Park's call history
박검사 통화내역입니다
the day you blew three billion won.
30억을 날린 날.
- Prosecutor Park? - Yeah.
- 박 검사님? - 응.
You overheard Prosecutor Kim on the phone in the hallway
김 검사의 통화를 우연히 들었나? 복도에서
and ran into Prosecutor Park at the golf driving range?
그리고 박검사와 마주쳤다. 골프연습장에서?
That may not be
그렇지 않을 수도 있습니다
a coincidence.
우연의 일치.
Then...
그럼...
Look into it.
살펴보세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
What do I tell Mr. Kang, though?
그런데 강 선생님께 뭐라고 말해야 할까요?
He told you to do nothing but stay alive.
아무것도 하지 말고 살아 있으라고 하더군요.
Don't get on his nerves. He doesn't have time for that.
그의 신경을 건드리지 마십시오. 그 사람은 그럴 시간이 없어요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Why do you keep coming to me? You love risking your life, anyway.
왜 자꾸 나한테 찾아오는데? 어쨌든 당신은 목숨을 걸고 싶어합니다.
The universe may decide when I live or die
내가 살거나 죽을 때를 우주가 결정할 수도 있다
but the Presidential election is soon.
하지만 곧 대통령 선거가 있어요.
Who becomes the next leader is up to the people.
차기 리더는 누구인가 사람들까지.
Exactly.
정확히.
Here.
여기.
Who's going to win?
누가 이길까요?
It's one or the other, anyway.
어쨌든 그것은 둘 중 하나입니다.
Why so confused?
왜 그렇게 혼란스러워?
The public opinion polls keep changing.
여론조사는 계속 바뀌고 있다.
I can't predict anything.
나는 아무것도 예측할 수 없습니다.
Gosh, old man.
이런, 늙은이.
You talk like a gentleman, but order me around like a maid.
당신은 신사처럼 말해요. 하지만 하녀처럼 나에게 명령을 내린다.
Here.
여기.
This one.
이것.
He'll take the jewel and rise.
그는 보석을 가지고 일어날 것입니다.
KIM YUN-CHEOL OF THE DAEHAN CENTRAL PARTY
김윤철 대한중앙당의
Kim Yun-cheol from the ruling party?
여당 김윤철?
Having no change of government sounds
정부 소리가 바뀌지 않음
like the best scenario possible.
가능한 최고의 시나리오처럼요.
Damn it, he's awake.
젠장, 그 사람 깨어났어.
I got it done.
나는 그것을 끝냈다.
Good work.
잘했어요.
SEOUL CENTRAL DISTRICT COURT
서울중앙지방법원
This contains all records of illegal funds for the new assemblymen
여기에는 불법 자금에 대한 모든 기록이 포함되어 있습니다. 신임 국회의원들을 위해
and the former and the current Presidents from the last election.
그리고 역대 대통령과 현직 대통령 지난 선거부터요.
Including Mr. Park Gwang-to, the former President.
박광토씨를 비롯해 전 대통령.
Are you surprised?
놀랐나요?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Illegal funds
불법자금
for the former and current Presidents...
전·현직 대통령들에게…
What a kid.
정말 좋은 아이입니다.
You thought Presidents would do better?
대통령이 더 잘할 거라고 생각했나요?
Nam-yong took these files while in the National Election Commission.
남용이가 이 파일들을 가져갔어 중앙선거관리위원회에 있을 때.
I could only get my hands on them because you kept his son captive.
나는 그들에게 손을 댈 수 밖에 없었어 당신이 그의 아들을 포로로 가두었기 때문입니다.
I knew it.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다.
So, Tae-seong
그러니까 태성아.
was not a bait
미끼가 아니었어
but was being held captive.
그러나 포로로 잡혀 있었습니다.
Are you disappointed I didn't tell you sooner?
실망했나요? 내가 더 일찍 말하지 않았나요?
No, sir.
아니요, 선생님.
I'll get to end Nam-yong's career
남용의 경력을 끝내겠다
and you've become more powerful with those files
그리고 당신은 더욱 강해졌습니다 그 파일들로
so I'm glad.
그래서 기쁘다.
That's right.
좋아요.
How it ends always matters more than the way there.
어떻게 끝나는지는 항상 중요하다 거기 가는 길보다.
I want to share this power with you.
이 힘을 여러분과 나누고 싶습니다.
What do you say?
당신은 무엇을 말합니까?
It's a chance to join the real power circle.
기회다 진정한 권력 서클에 합류하기 위해.
He means the Suojae.
수오재를 뜻하는데요.
Everyone, please rise.
여러분, 일어나주세요.
Announce Tae-seong as not guilty.
태성을 무죄로 선언한다.
You want to join the real power circle
당신은 진정한 권력 서클에 합류하고 싶습니다
the shadow government that runs Korea?
한국을 운영하는 그림자 정부?
This is just a small entry fee for that.
이것은 단지 약간의 입장료일 뿐입니다.
Everyone, please be seated.
모두 자리에 앉으세요.
DEFENDANT
피고인
JUDGE
판사
Where's the Defendant?
피고인은 어디에 있나요?
Sorry, Your Honor. I can't reach him right now
죄송합니다, 재판장님. 지금은 그 사람에게 연락할 수 없어요
but he should be here any minute.
하지만 그 사람은 곧 여기 있을 거예요.
JUDGE
판사
It's been ten minutes now.
이제 10분이 지났습니다.
Do we need to wait any longer?
더 이상 기다려야 하나요?
Sorry about that.
죄송해요.
Tae-seong is holding a press conference.
태성이 기자회견을 하고 있다.
- Right now? - You sure?
- 지금 바로? - 정말요?
In the past life
전생에
Tae-seong took his own life with a letter claiming his innocence
태성이 스스로 목숨을 끊었다 그의 결백을 주장하는 편지와 함께
which made the public turn from cold to empathetic.
대중의 관심을 돌리게 만든 것 차가운 것에서 공감하는 것까지.
And Nam-yong, who'd lost his son
그리고 아들을 잃은 남용이
became the Chief Justice.
대법원장이 되었습니다.
I knew
나는 알고 있었다
I was faking my work experience
나는 직장 경험을 속이고 있었다
yet still included my teaching assistantship and internship
아직 포함되어 있어요 나의 조교 및 인턴십
as work experience on my application to JB Daehan.
직장 경험으로는 JB 대한 지원서에 있어요.
PRESS CONFERENCE FOR HWANG TAE-SEONG AND HIS UNFAIR HIRING ALLEGATIONS
황태성 기자간담회 그리고 그의 부당한 채용 혐의
I apologize.
사과드립니다.
I'm Gong Hyeon-do of Yujeong Daily.
유정일보 공현도 입니다.
When did you submit
언제 제출했나요?
your application to JB Daehan?
JB대한에 지원하셨나요?
I was tipped off that you applied after the deadline.
나는 제보를 받았다 마감일 이후에 신청한 것입니다.
I submitted it to the HR
HR에 제출했어요
after getting hired.
채용된 후.
Tae-seong!
태성!
Darn it.
젠장.
Yeah.
응.
I'm Seok Jeong-ho.
저는 석정호입니다.
Sin-jin will try to kill Tae-seong.
신진은 태성을 죽이려고 한다.
Guard him, no matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도 그를 지켜주세요.
Who am I?
나는 누구입니까?
I'm Seok Jeong-ho, alright?
저는 석정호예요, 그렇죠?
Gosh, why is it raining out of nowhere?
맙소사, 왜 갑자기 비가 내리는 걸까요?
What's with the weather?
날씨는 어때요?
I told you to bring an umbrella.
우산을 가져오라고 했어요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Your father is
당신의 아버지는
Justice Hwang Nam-yong, correct?
황남용 판사 맞죠?
Yes.
예.
Have I been kidnapped?
내가 납치됐나요?
Are you stupid?
당신은 바보입니까?
I saved your life!
내가 당신의 생명을 구했어요!
But
하지만
people will keep coming, trying to kill you.
사람들이 계속 오고, 당신을 죽이려고합니다.
And we can't save you on time every time.
그리고 우리는 매번 당신을 제 시간에 맞춰 구할 수는 없습니다.
Who's trying to kill me?
누가 나를 죽이려고 하는 걸까요?
What did I ever do wrong?
내가 무슨 잘못을 한 적이 있나요?
You had your father get you a job at JB Daehan.
당신은 아버지에게 일자리를 구해 달라고 했어요 JB대한에서.
I don't deserve death for that!
나는 그런 이유로 죽을 자격이 없습니다!
No
아니요
that deserves death and more to those who want your father
그건 죽음에 합당한 일이고 그 이상이다. 누가 네 아버지를 원하는지
to become the Chief Justice.
대법원장이 되려면.
They need you to die for people to become empathetic
그들은 당신이 죽기를 원해요 사람들이 공감할 수 있도록
so your father can finally become the Chief Justice.
드디어 네 아버지가 될 수 있게 대법원장.
That's ridiculous.
말도 안 돼요.
- Is it? Really? - Hey.
- 그렇죠? 정말? - 여기요.
You're saying
당신은 말하고 있어요
it's not ridiculous
말도 안 돼
that you got hired with the lowest test score?
당신이 채용됐다고 시험 점수가 가장 낮나요?
Stop.
멈추다.
Man!
남성!
Do you want to live?
살고 싶나요?
Yes.
예.
Strike first, then.
그럼 먼저 공격하세요.
I'm Song Na-yeon of Daejin Daily.
대진데일리 송나연 입니다.
Did Justice Hwang
황 판사님이 그랬나요?
also help you get a job at JB Daehan?
그리고 JB대한에 취업하는데 도움을 주셨나요?
Yes, my father said
네, 아버지가 말씀하셨어요
the written exam and the interview were just for formality
필기시험과 면접이 있었습니다 그냥 형식적으로
and that I'd get the job, no matter what.
그리고 무슨 일이 있어도 나는 그 일자리를 얻을 것이라고 말했습니다.
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
사직서
The Judiciary is in a huge shock once again.
사법부는 큰 충격에 빠졌다 다시 한 번.
Justice Hwang, under the allegations
황 판사, 혐의로
of colluding with unfair hiring practices and taking bribes
부당한 채용 관행에 공모했다는 그리고 뇌물을 받고
submitted his letter of resignation.
사직서를 제출했다.
The prosecution explained
검찰은 해명했다.
Justice Hwang allegedly took bribes from a construction company
황 판사, 뇌물 수수 의혹 건설회사 출신
and used his networks
그의 네트워크를 이용했고
to get his son a job he didn't qualify for
아들에게 자격이 없는 직업을 갖기 위해
and that they planned on summoning him for questioning soon.
그리고 그들은 그를 소환할 계획을 세웠어요 곧 질문을 위해.
Justice Hwang submitted his letter of resignation this morning
황 판사가 제출한 오늘 아침에 그의 사직서
and left the court without a word.
그리고 말없이 법정을 떠났다.
The prosecution is aware
검찰도 알고 있다
of Justice Hwang receiving bribes
뇌물을 받은 황 판사
and his involvement in unfair hiring practices.
그리고 그의 개입 부당한 채용 관행에
They will announce a date for his questioning soon.
그들은 발표할 것이다 곧 심문 날짜가 다가오네요.
Chief Justice Jeon Heung-woo is
전흥우 대법원장은
also taking responsibility by resigning
또한 사임하여 책임을 진다.
for the damaged reputation of the Judiciary.
손상된 평판에 대해 사법부의.
The Office of the President has made
대통령실이 만들었습니다.
an official nomination of Baek Yi-seok
백이석 공식 지명
as the next Chief Justice.
차기 대법원장으로.
Power changes are happening rapidly within the Judiciary
권력 변화가 빠르게 일어나고 있다 사법부 내에서
and the employees within the court are wondering
그리고 법원 직원들 궁금하다
if this will signal a reformation
이것이 개혁의 신호라면
of the whole system.
전체 시스템의.
I'll invite you to the room with the best views once you retire.
방으로 초대할게요 은퇴하면 최고의 전망을 즐길 수 있습니다.
Here.
여기.
Your son will have to pay for what he's done.
당신의 아들이 돈을 지불해야 할 것입니다 그가 한 일 때문에.
But I'll let you get away
하지만 널 떠나게 해줄게
with non-custodial investigation and probation.
비구속 수사로 그리고 집행유예.
But of course
하지만 물론
you'd better not let Suojae hear about our deal.
수오재한테는 듣지 않는 게 좋을 거야 우리 거래에 대해.
What a pathetic man.
정말 한심한 사람이군요.
He got bitten in the ass by his own son.
그는 자신의 아들에게 엉덩이를 물렸습니다.
Here we are.
여기 있습니다.
Don't trust anyone here.
여기 누구도 믿지 마세요.
And don't speak unless you're asked a question.
그리고 말을 하지 마세요 질문을 받지 않는 한.
Don't be surprised by anything you see or hear.
놀라지 마세요 당신이 보거나 듣는 모든 것에 의해.
You'll look stupid.
당신은 바보처럼 보일 것입니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Is today
오늘인가
the day we fill our treasure chest?
보물상자를 채우는 날은?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Mr. Han
한씨
you know why I'm still going so strong to this day?
내가 왜 아직도 그렇게 강한지 알아? 오늘까지?
I don't know, sir.
모르겠어요.
Because the world is the same.
세상은 똑같으니까요.
It never changes, does it?
절대 변하지 않죠?
Introduce yourself.
자신을 소개하세요.
I'm Judge Lee Han-young at the Seoul Central Court.
판사 이한영 입니다 서울중앙법원에서.
I'm here to serve the nation and our people.
나는 여기 있다 국가와 국민을 위해 봉사하겠습니다.
Take a seat.
자리에 앉으세요.
This is a special activity fund from the National Intelligence Service.
특별활동기금입니다 국정원 출신.
This is from the prosecution.
검찰에서 나온 내용입니다.
This is from the Ministry of National Defense.
이것은 국방부에서.
This is from the National Police Agency.
경찰청에서 나온 내용입니다.
Alright, then.
그럼요.
Let's serve our nation.
우리 민족을 위해 봉사합시다.
These crazy bastards!
이 미친 놈들아!
THE JUDGE RETURNS
판사가 돌아오다
The elimination has begun.
제거가 시작되었습니다.
They have a record of everywhere we've been
그들은 기록을 가지고 있습니다 우리가 가본 모든 곳에서
and our call history!
그리고 우리 통화 기록!
Sin-jin is going to catch on soon.
신진이가 곧 따라잡을 예정이다.
I'll get rid of Gwang-to, who relies on mere shamans
광토를 없애겠습니다. 단순한 무당에게 의지하는 자
and become the leader of Suojae.
그리고 수오재의 리더가 되어보세요.
So, who is that?
그럼 저 사람은 누구인가요?
Judge Lee Han-young.
이한영 판사.
And Sin-jin is behind it?
그리고 그 배후에는 신진이 있다?
The prosecution will indict him while in custody
검찰이 그를 기소할 것이다 구금되어 있는 동안
and Judge Lee, whom we met at the Suojae, will be on the case.
그리고 수오재에서 만난 이 판사님, 사건에 걸릴 것입니다.
Hey, Byeon. Let's save a life.
안녕, 변. 생명을 구하자.
Sin-jin and Gwang-to.
신진과 광토.
I must stop both of them
둘 다 그만둬야겠어
or the country's justice will be gone for good.
아니면 나라의 정의가 사라질 것이다 영원히.
Subtitles by: Min-sun Kim
자막: 김민선